A Guide to the Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Business Records, 1934-1957
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Business Records, 1934-1957
The Library of Virginia
1124168-1124171, 1124307-1124314, 1128236-1128256
33 volumes (7223 p.). Two volumes missing cover and spine.
Lee County
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Payroll Account Ledger, 1955-1957, includes private information. Do not serve. There are no restrictions for serving rest of collection.
Acquisition Information
These materials came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from Lee County.
Historical Information
The Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated and the Benedict Coal Corporation operated coal mines in Lee County, Virginia, during the mid-twentieth century with offices located in the town of St. Charles, Virginia. The Benvir Coal Company purchased controlling interest of the Benedict Coal Corporation during the mid-1950's.
Scope and Content Information
Various business records, 1934-1957, of the Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated and the Benedict Coal Corporation. The majority of records relate to activities of the Benedict Coal Corporation which was purchased by Benvir Coal Company during the mid-1950's.
Two trial balance books of Benedict Coal Corporation, 1944-1955, used to check that the debits and credits in a double-entry bookkeeping ledger are equal at the end of each month. It lists the titles of accounts, date, and the amount of money debited or credited in that particular month. Accounts listed in volume include general ledger, petty ledger, cash, mining, payroll, sales ledger, and scrip change fund. Information found in trial balance book was taken from cash journals and transferred to appropriate ledger.
Three general ledgers of Benedict Coal Corporation, 1946-1957, and one general ledger of the Benvir Coal Company, 1955-1957, that record the corporations' controlling and operating accounts which include interest account, coal sales, depreciation, insurance claims, social security tax, store salaries, ventilation, drainage, unemployment insurance, and mine operating costs. Each individual account lists date of transactions, amount debited, amount credited, and page number or account number where transaction can be found in corresponding cash journal or voucher record book. Information related to individual accounts found in general ledger was taken from trial balance books, voucher record books, cash journals, and expense journals. General ledger (1946-1949) includes an index listing accounts in alphabetical order and page number where they can be found. General ledgers (1950-1957) also include an index listing accounts in alphabetical order and account number, rather than page number, where they can be found. General ledger (1950- 1953) is missing its cover and spine.
Ten cash journals of Benedict Coal Corporation, August 1948-September 1957, and four cash journals of the Benvir Coal Company, August 1955-September 1957 that record the corporation's transactions on a daily basis similar to a daybook. Information found in each volume includes date of transaction, form of transaction, and amount owed and paid. The cash amount of transaction is listed under the name of ledger where it eventually was transferred. Ledgers listed include general ledger, petty ledger, cash ledger, payroll ledger, sales ledger, scrip ledger, store sales ledger, etc. Page numbers and account numbers found in many transactions correspond to page numbers and account numbers found in corresponding general ledgers. At the end of each month, the bookkeeper subtracted the cash received from cash paid to calculate the total balance for each ledger. The amount was then placed in the trial balance book and eventually transferred to the corresponding ledger. Loose papers (correspondence, receipts, etc.,) found in several ledgers were removed and placed in folder.
Two mining supplies voucher ledgers of Benedict Coal Corporation, 1948-1953, that record on a monthly basis how much the corporation owed suppliers for the purchase on credit of mining supplies or services. They list the names of companies from whom the corporation made purchases, area or department of corporation for whom the purchase was made (ventilation, electrical, machine repair, delivery, engineering, etc.), and amount paid.
Depreciation accounts ledger of Benedict Coal Corporation, 1934-1944, that records on an annual basis the amount by which the corporation's property and equipment decreased in value. It lists the name of property and equipment (mine cars, trucks, ropes, telephone lines, office furniture, service stations, etc.), it's original value, and amount it depreciated over time. Loose documents found in volume related to the company's depreciation schedule were removed and placed in folder. The cover of volume reads "Trial Balance."
Two voucher record books of the Benedict Coal Corporation, 1948-1955, and one voucher record book of the Benvir Coal Company, 1955-1957, that record on a monthly basis how much the corporations owed suppliers for the purchase on credit of supplies or services. They are similar to an accounts payable ledger. Information found in the volumes includes the names of companies from whom the corporations purchased supplies and services on credit, the amount of payment, and the name of the account from which the payment was expended. Transactions were transferred from voucher record book to general ledger. Account numbers found at the end of each month's transactions correspond to account numbers in corresponding general ledgers. Loose documents found in Benvir Coal Company voucher record book were removed and placed in folder.
Two cash flow ledgers of Benedict Coal Corporation, 1949-1955, and one cash flow ledger of Benvir Coal Company, 1955-1956, used to calculate on a monthly basis the amount of cash remaining to pay wages of the corporation's employees following the payment of debts. It records the expenses incurred by employees including medical, rental fees, scrip advances, lights, store accounts, burial, union dues, and overdrafts and payroll expenses such as Social Security tax and unemployment insurance. It also records expenses related to mining operations including drainage, ventilation, truck delivery, timbers, and machine repairs. Each of the previous were totalled and subtracted from the gross payroll to determine the cash remaining to pay employees.
Petty ledger of Benvir Coal Company, 1955-1957, that records accounts of little importance. They are the accounts of individuals perhaps employees. Information found in each account includes date of transaction, page number of corresponding cash journal or voucher record book where information was transferred, amount owed, and amount paid. Accounts arranged in alphabetical order by surname of individual.
Coal shipment record book of Benvir Coal Company, 1955-1957. It records monthly the type (block, round, stoker, carbon, nut and slack), tonnage, and price of coal shipped to Holmes-Darst Coal Corporation by Benvir Coal Company from its various mines. Various loose documents were found in volume. They include receipts, coal shipment accounts containing information from volume, payroll, vacation payroll for year 1956- 1957, service station account, and balance sheets of company listing assets, liablilities, and net worth. The various payroll accounts list the names of employees, amount of wages, taxes withheld, vacation pay, other expenses taken from wages, and net amount of wages. Documents were removed from volume and placed in folder.
Payroll Account ledger of Benvir Coal Company, August 1955 - May 1957, that records monthly the individual payroll accounts of employees. Information found in each account includes name of employee, month paid, amount of taxable earning, withholding tax, vacation pay (yes or no), and an unidentified account perhaps Social Security tax withheld. The front page of ledger records the totals of each category. Ledger is missing cover and spine.
Checkbook ledger of Benvir Coal Company, 1957, that contains check stubs and blank checks. Information found on check stubs includes check number, date check issued, name of company or individual to whom check was written, and amount of check.
Arrangement
Volumes arranged chronologically within each series.
Contents List
- Benedict Coal Corporation Trial Balance Book, 1944-1949
- Benedict Coal Corporation Trial Balance Book, 1950-1955
- Benedict Coal Corporation General Ledger, 1946-1949
- Benedict Coal Corporation General Ledger, 1950-1953
- Benedict Coal Corporation General Ledger, 1950-1957
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, General Ledger, 1955-1957
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1948-1949
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1949
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1949-1950
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1950
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1951
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1951-1952
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1952-1953
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1953-1954
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1954-1955
- Benedict Coal Corporation Cash Journal, 1955-1957
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Cash Journal, 1955
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Cash Journal, 1955-1956
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Cash Journal, 1956-1957
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Cash Journal, 1957
- Benedict Coal Corporation Mining Supplies Vouchers Ledger, 1948-1950
- Benedict Coal Corporation Mining Supplies Vouchers Ledger, 1950-1953
- Benedict Coal Corporation Depreciation Accounts Ledger, 1934-1944
- Benedict Coal Corporation Voucher Record Book, 1948-1952
- Benedict Coal Corporation Voucher Record Book, 1952-1955
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Voucher Record Book, 1955-1957
- Benedict Coal Corporation Monthly Cash Flow Ledger, 1949-1951
- Benedict Coal Corporation Monthly Cash Flow Ledger, 1952-1955
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Monthly Cash Flow Ledger, 1955-1956
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Petty Ledger, 1955-1957
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Coal Shipment Record Book, 1955-1957
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Payroll Account Ledger, 1955-1957
- Benvir Coal Company, Incorporated, Checkbook Ledger, 1957